You had just finished a year worth 30
million, which is crazy, but it's nothing
compared to today.
And what we did for 4 and a half.
You still see yourself a lot on Wiad Total.  The
first goal is a billion in
turnover, which for us means 1
million euros per year.  VOD which is the
big thing we can do today in the
group, it's 90% of my time, there's an
all-encompassing vo.  [music] There
are no great results without
great effort.  He is an entrepreneur
because his whole family believes in it.
[music] I feel a very strong
social calling to bring
people [music] into the world who will change
something.
Within the random there was a
small window of secondaries which
according to me is a big taboo in Italy.  I
made a couple of million.
He is Paolo De Nadai, born in 1988 and
founder of WROAD, perhaps the
best-known travel company in Italy.  Here it
raised $58 million in a
round led by Airbnb to expand
into the United States.  News reports
say Airbnb has acquired about 10%
of the company, so if you do the math,
the valuation could be closer to $
400 million to $500 million.  And Paolo, who
still owns a significant stake through his holding company
, could be a hundred
millionaire on paper by the time he's not even 40 years old.  Very different from 2022
when I first met him
.  At that time, Wead had closed the year
with a turnover of almost 30 million,
but it grew year after year, reaching
25 and exceeding 100 million.  If in
that interview Paolo
told me about his journey from the school he
founded at 18 to the birth of
Wead, this time I want to understand what
happens next, what the challenges are
today and what has changed.  But what's it like to have
such a busy life managing several
companies moving one child after
another?  And that's why I also invaded the
house to have dinner with the whole
family.
Hey,
good evening.  Hi Marcello, welcome.   How is it going
?  The last time I made
a clip with you here was 4 years ago and you
would have been at most the
third or fourth on my entrepreneur interview playlist, but we're at 100.
Exactly.  Hey, you've had a great run.
How much has happened between that day
and today?  so many.
However, I had to wait for Paolo because
duty called and I witnessed a couple
of calls he made.
Get to know each other and see if we can have
a beautiful, professional wedding together
and turn VOD upside down.
While Paolo was on the video call, they
also called him on the phone and he
replied: "Double call, I
missed this."
And the third is doing too many things
at once, not doing any of them
thoroughly and well, which then in
the end, damn it, leaves you with a life that
is insipid because you've done everything but you've
done nothing.  You realize it too
late with the famous checkpoint before the
startup, so I am by training
deeply against it.  You have to do
something, little fella.
While Paolo was finishing his calls, I took the
opportunity to take a look
around.   You did
n't get the audio, did you?  I've been
recording some audio, only of non-
incriminating things.
Non-compromising, exactly.
But do you receive phone calls while you're on a
call?  You change, you respond, you attack.
How does it work?  There
is a rule here.  When
investors or the CFO call you, you
always have to answer "or the wife."  Three people you
always have to answer to.
And who was this group?   She
was the CFO.  The CFO.
And then you still do the interviews.
I believe that the density of talent, the
quality of the people you bring on
board, makes the company.
It is one of the activities with the highest
added value.  What tasks do you do
during the day?  post communication
of the round in which I had underestimated
the media impact.  Right now
I have a backlog of emails and LinkedIn
messages that kind of happened to me
during the round because the
closing phase is really never over
until you have the money in the bank
and now you have it in the bank.
Now they have arrived.  But a transfer of
58 million
and the BNB was the IDE Investor, but
there were also the prorates of all the
current investors who followed the
advisor siby who followed, so
there were more transfers the big number of the
current account from SFO gave us the screenshot
is always very cool.  So I was behind
enjoying people in the
closing phase, but then after
even worse,
worse, after a quick tour it was
time to ask him how he
managed to convince Airbnb to
invest.  You and I met in
Silicon Valley last year, and
you were like, "Maybe I'd like to go
international. I'll take a look around and
find out about this
investment news."  What happened from that
day until today?
In one year we managed to open
US.  The first truly
encouraging signs.  Americans are
incredible, super direct, very tough
in the negotiation part.  It's
truly a world, a way of doing
business that's definitely different, straight
to the point, and I'm enjoying it.  I
have always been and continue to be
a great supporter of networking,
so one thing leads to another.  Adventurers are
useful, financial advisors are
useful to close rounds, but if he manages
to do it with networking, in my opinion he will have
a much, much greater ease and speed of generating
a reaction.   They
also met their new general manager for
the United States
through the network with an introduction by Luca
Querella, co-founder of Benny Spons who
is also their advisor.  All the founders
of Benny Spons are also investors in
Weoad and by spying on the balance sheets, however
Paolo is also an investor in Benny Spons, a
significant share.  In fact, at the time, he was the
first one to make the intro for me to make the
video with them.  This is to say that one
of Paolo's superpowers is
networking.  In fact, over the years I have
met him on a thousand different occasions, from the
Italian Funders Fund to Conf Commercio.
Okay, but how did he convince Airbnb to
invest?  Lately, I've been very
positive about the Italian ecosystem and
I see that there's a much greater propensity,
especially on the part of Americans, to
invest in our country.  And I
remember when I called
Brian, the first thing he did was
emphasize his Italian origins.   I
don't remember if the typical grandmother is from I don't
remember which Italian town.  You
said you are very Italian, you are one of us.
In my opinion, we Italians are actually
loved by everyone, and I think
you've even started to respect us a lot.  It's partly
thanks to Bendy Spons that he's creating
a masterpiece of entrepreneurial history
in these months of dialogue with
America.  In every meeting they do well.
So we think of Jetr who now has
done mega rounds with an American, a
good one has done rounds with an American,
now the ex another American, that is, less and
less prejudice against
us Italians who achieve the feat.   I wo
n't deny that there are some
aspects of Italian bureaucracy that are
difficult to understand
there.  How long did the negotiations last?
Uh Marcello, the first email was in mid-
October and we closed 6-7 months later.
It's actually relatively quick
to get to a rough estimate, right?  Then
the issue is to transform that dev sheet into the
contract.  I remember the documentary was
like 250 pages, something like that,
right?  The easiest thing when you film
the temp, you know, is the size of the ticket, the
evaluation, the principal of mass
governance, but then after that you have to
dissect two pages of shehet in 250
pages in which you regulate everything.
How many lawyers did you hire for
this?  Well done Marcello,
because for my
mini-operation in comparison we already had
days and days of negotiations with a
lot of lawyers. In hindsight, one of the
things I appreciated most was the
relationship with the lawyers.  There was
us as Weoad, obviously Airbnb,
the investors.
Excellent.  Simply put, we had lead
investments in Series B14 with BNB, which
is an industrial investor.
However, there were two different needs
in finding an agreement between the parties and
there was a great interest in managing and
therefore remaining lawyers.  I recognized
in hindsight the importance of having created
a good relationship with the various parties.
Your lawyer is really like
a coach who gives you the
right advice.  He is the ambassador who
brings the message, who receives the
message, who makes you think, who
keeps you clear.  For me, as for all
entrepreneurs, when you make
a higher round every time, the first time,
well done, for lawyers it's the umpteenth and
therefore they already know in advance what
the problems might be, which
are the points you have to give
up, the ones on which it is instead important
to find a compromise, etc.  It's the
same counterparts.  And the other
important thing is that this is a deal that
is not a finish line, but a
starting point.  Then you have to make this money
work for you.  That is, now we have to make
Wirad work in the US and become
a global brand and we have to do it
together with our investors, our
partners.  So it can't be a
negotiation where I crush you, but it has to
be a negotiation where we're
all happy and happy to have
become partners.
What is the strategy now for going to the
United States?
At WiRoad we guarantee that you travel
with people your own age, we guarantee
that you travel in the language you want
with a mood.  Sometimes you go on a
more adventurous trip, sometimes more, I do
n't know, relaxing.  So opening US for us
is actually an extension of a site we
already had which was an English site.
We already offered concomg in
English, but we were
deliberately geolocalizing
performance marketing and activation
marketing.  We do a lot of
community events in Europe, the UK, Ireland, then
actually with Docom in English
we also do marketing in Holland, in the
Nordics.  But now we have to open up
to the United States.  How will we do it?  There is a
whole digital part of performance marketing
, so it is national across the
entire United States.  Our
reasoning is that there is no reason why the
100 million we make in Italy cannot be
made in all the countries of Europe.
If Europe alone can be worth 500,
America must be worth at least 500,
potentially much more because
America is immense, it's a huge
opportunity, but as all investors always tell us,
even with Airbnb
etc., you can also get
hurt a lot because you can also waste
a lot of money quickly.  In the
travel world, Google usually reigns supreme.
Of course, because I search for a trip to
Amsterdam and I find the trip to
Amsterdam.  We are an anomaly, so
because for us the
main channel is actually meta, Facebook and Instagram,
so this allowed us to enter
a special meta project that
makes us test with their
sophisticated tools in the US,
so in reality we already had some
metrics, so we already had some KPIs on
which we built the business plan and
with those KPIs, with those metrics already
validated we then carried out the fundraising
and on the basis of that experience we are
now deploying the goal, the
marketing plan which therefore includes a part
of performance marketing, I would say
national.
Have you started yet?  Yes, yes, we have already
started with some very
promising metrics.
There are already some conversions.
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
And then City Strategy and now
we have taken Austin Washington as a hub
where we can also do City Strategy on the field.
For example, we held the
first section bootcamp in Austin and have already
selected the first 32 group leaders who
will lead the trips.  It is much easier
for us to open the United States than
Portugal which spoiler we will do the
Portuguese.  When you open a Wroad there is
a theme of feel rate, supply and demand,
so a WiRoad makes sense when you have
10 people to travel with because you want to
make friends and therefore the theme is I put
a new language online from scratch, I
offer you 100 trips.  If I have 100
reservations, one per trip,
it's a problem, I can't confirm
anyone.  I need to get to 108 per
trip to confirm this.  So when
we launch a new country it's all a
game of how many destinations
I put in, how many dates, how I fill them.
Instead for the United States it was much
easier because we already have the
English website and so we already have online,
I mean we already make thousands of packs
in English of Weavers, so we
already have Ah, already made thousands of
packs in English.
Oh, sure.  With the English, with the
Irish, the Dutch, the Swedes.
In short, Wirod already had trips in
English where they already carried around 10,000
passengers and therefore to attack the
American market they didn't need to
recreate the infrastructure, but everything was
already ready.  It's just for
advertising.
Italy is the first market, it's 100
million, then Germany, the second
market, then we have Spain because it's the
one we opened as the first
international market, France and the UK are
tied where we make a little
less than 10,000 bucks.  It's a good foundation to
build on with the Americans.   It's
simply a matter of saying, "Okay, there's
Japan 360," we can have six
English people, one Irishman, an XA who lives in
Dubai and three Americans, don't I have to
put it online from scratch?  So those three
Americans who would have been erased,
whether it was just them or three, actually
become the undo, 12th 1st participant of
that journey that was already starting.  Now it is
the Goot to Market US, the
marketing and localization machine.  I
guarantee you can [music] do in
your free time the activity you want with
new friends from a sports event in your city
to dinner, generally, I don't
know, running club in the morning, yoga,
aperitif, testing, dinners, has the
weekend behind the house, has the trip to
Alaska, Patagonia.  At weekends,
localization is essential, so if
you are English it is obvious that the weekend
for you is, I don't know, in Scotland.  If you are an
American it will be in Aspen.  And in fact
our American GM agreed
that in the first phase on the US side we will
focus on our
flagship which is the more adventurous long-haul journey
.
Why should Airbnb invest in
[music] Weoad?  Well, first of all I'm very
proud because it's a great validation of
what we're doing.  When he
called Brian, there was a
great harmony of vision and the
belief that the more you have, the more
social media becomes an element in
everyday life.  Then there is
the need for real-life
experiences, connections, a sense of
belonging.
Ok, but the United States is the
most difficult market in the world.  How will We deal with
the competition?  There are some countries
that have no players, so they are
completely a blue can, others where
there are players, but they are a
bit older establishments.  In America, three
great references do
similar things.  The biggest one is called Intrepy
Travel which makes a billion and two with Tiki,
G Adventure, Top Deck, Backroads, but
there are some different nuances, for
us 15 people it is the right side to
get to know each other well, transform
strangers into friends.  the fact that the
group leader is not the tour guide,
he is the one who does the ice breaking, who
takes care of the leadership of the group, starting
the conversations, maybe solving the
logistical parts about
punctuality, but then when you are in Machu
Picchu there is a local guide who
explains the history of Machu Picchu to you, it is not
his responsibility, he sleeps with you, lives
with you, it is the first time he has traveled with
you to that country, so there is an energy,
a discovery.  No,
the competitors don't have this,
do they?  Then we were fully digital from the
beginning, while others were perhaps the
players born decades ago who then
tried to digitize the focus on the
age group, not mixing the
age groups because today we started out
25-35, then we added the 35 plus
because our repeaters had grown
and now we have added the
18-25.
With almost 60 million to attack a
new market, it is possible to throw away
money inefficiently.  So
what are the KPIs that Paolo looks at?
KPI stands for key performance indicator,
which is a cool way of saying what
data we want to measure to prove
we're successful.  It could be
revenue, it could be
customer acquisition cost, it could be
operating margin, a lot of things.
What would be a positive scenario for the US market a year from now?
Our board also asked us, so
I'm prepared.  Let's say I have no doubts
about the quality rate of the trips.  I would be
very surprised if it went badly from an
experience feedback standpoint.  So the KPI we
look at is the conversion rate in Germany,
our second market.  We
expect significantly
better conversion rates across the entire
marketing funnel than in Germany.
Paolo replied that the conversion rate
is the KPI that matters to him and
the important thing is that it is better than
when they entered Germany,
their first market, with the idea
that since then they have learned a lot about
how to enter a new market.  The
conversion rate is how many people
buy a trip after seeing the
advertisement.  But now let's get back to Paolo
because in addition to this
Airbnb investment, Paolo has his mind on a lot of
other things.  He is president of the
young entrepreneurs group of Conf Commercio
Milano, a partner in Founders Fund, a father
of three children, and also a founder of new
companies.  [music]
Analyzing hundreds of entrepreneurs,
managers and people who have built
important companies or careers, I
realized one thing.  At a certain point, the
difference isn't just made by your
skills, but also by the
clarity with which you make decisions, the
way you manage stress, your
priorities, and the balance between work and
personal life, because building something
great is a marathon, not a sprint.  And
if the head doesn't take it, sooner or later
the rest of the world suffers too.  And that's why I think
psychology can be
incredibly valuable, not only when you have a problem
to solve, but also as a tool
to get to know yourself better, make
decisions more clearly, and build
a balance that allows you to perform at your
best in the long run.  This is also why I'm
telling you about Uno Bravo today.
I also made a dedicated video with
its founder.  Uno Bravo is a
psychology center that helps you find a
professional who's right for you.  You fill out an
initial questionnaire to collect
what you are experiencing.  You'll be matched
with a psychologist who best suits
your needs, and you can have a
free initial meeting.  It helps you
understand if you feel comfortable and if it makes
sense to start a
[musical] journey together.  If you decide to
continue, the course is completely
online and can be adapted to your schedule.  I'll
leave you the code for Scani 10 in the description,
which gives you a discount on the first
sessions after the initial
introductory meeting.  If you want to know more,
you can find everything in the description.  It's not a
magic solution, but if we invest time
and money in improving our
skills, perhaps it makes sense to
also invest in the person who
has to put those skills into practice
every day.
A billion things have changed since we made our last video
.  Let's make a list of all the things
that happened.  You had just
finished a year worth 30 million, which is
crazy, but it's nothing compared to
today.
And what did we do?  4 and a half.
It was in your expectations.   He
actually wants to be a little more
ambitious.  Guys, we're doing
business in really complex years,
eh.  Look, there was Covid, the
war in Ukraine, tariffs,
inflation, the war in Iran, the
media terrorism of the
fuel shortage, so they were
complex years, so in reality,
having done for 4 and me in 3 years in
these years here, I am very proud.  And
then since we met
we launched Brom Patenti.  Brom
patents, of which I am also an investor.
Brom was born from the fact that in many
countries the driving school process has
been innovated and digitalized.  In
Italy, however, we are still stuck in the
90s and this is why Brom Patente was born,
led by Luca Cozzarini.
That is, to make you understand, in France Ornica is
the French brom,
French brom, kkar went inside the
biggest giants of the global venture.
Let's say that new-generation driving schools
in France cover half of the
market.  Ornicar made up 30% of the
total market.  The number two player has just been purchased,
very recent news,
meaning 100% of the licenses have been placed in their hands
.  This is why
a driving license in France costs half as much as in
Italy.  Because obviously the moment
you streamline the process and use
digital to make the steps much easier on the
bureaucratic side, you
also put a much lower cost on the user.
And then there is another topic, the preparation
of the boys.  If you look at the
failure rate of driving tests in recent years
, it has increased significantly,
the failure rate has gone up to 40%
because there is a crazy law from '95 but it has been
repealed, which prohibits leer.
So listen carefully to the nonsense.  As a
certified driving school, I am required to
hold in-person lessons.
Of course, I did it in person.  In
all our driving schools, every
Wednesday at 2:00 pm we have our
instructor who is the teacher who gives the
lessons, almost nobody comes.  The
absurd thing is that the driving school is
required to hold the lesson in
person, the student is not required
to participate, so what does he do?  One goes
online and studies with uncertified people
, but then in 2026 we
did the 5-year 3-year distance learning with Covid,
you can do online university, you can
graduate, you can take all the subjects,
you can become a doctor, we are doing
surgical operations remotely and we ca
n't teach you about roundabouts,
priority, road signs.
This law is crazy.  So we're
also doing a lot of lobbying to
explain to the Ministry of Transport and
the motor vehicle authorities that this needs to
change.  I can't tell you how much ostrich
we're getting.  We can use
technology for everything related to the
bureaucratic process, which is why we
at Brom Patenti have
digitized it.  Booking your
medical appointment, uploading documents, and
booking your drivers—so you do
n't have to come to the
driving school yourself—
is more convenient depending on
where you live.  You can choose which
teacher to have.  We have a dashcam
that films the boy while he is
teaching and tells you his mistakes.  With
Paolo's track record,
Brom quickly attracted
the attention of investors, including
myself, of course,
as well as Leonardo Maria del Vecchio, Nicola
Drago, whom I interviewed, Luigi
Berlusconi, Sofia Goggia, and many others.
Brom was born from an internal We
Road program where young people spend 3 years
seeing all the functions of the company and
then can either become managers or
launch new projects.  Brom patente was
born because one of the guys inside
the company, we have a program
called High Potential Profile Program
that allows people, boys and
girls with high potential to see
a different function
of the company every 6 months, have direct access as
for the mentorship of an SE level and at the
end of the path be able to take over
either their company or a business unit.
Luca Cozzarini, the co-founder of Broom with me
, worked at Wood and at the end of
the Potential Profile course he
passed it because in any case it is not a
given, it is a very
intense program.
How old is he?  He was born in 1997 and
spent 3 years with us with this powerful
profile.  You see finance, you see
operations, you see tech, you see sales,
you see marketing, you see HR.  At the end
of this journey we decided to
launch brom.  Another guy Mautino
also did this program here, he
led Wiro Dix which is practically
worth half of our turnover.  I find
that doing Innovation within a company
is always complex, as it requires having one
person who has full ownership of the new
project to be launched and who must act
separately from the company processes, so
either it results in launching a new Unit within an
existing company or launching
a new startup.  In Luca's case,
Brun Patenti was launched.
This program is a bit of a way to find new executives too,
and it's been great.  And we provide
new leadership in-house.  But how does
Paul manage it all?  School zoo,
Weoad, broom, family
free time.
Well, right now my focus is
WeAD and e broom, so I have nothing else
work-wise.
Yes, we, which is the biggest thing we can
do today in the group,
it's 90% of my time and Brom where I
give him a 30 who is my cofounder, the CEO
of the company, he is very good, he
really manages the company great.  My
main contribution is on the
marketing side where I can give great
value to the institutional relations side
on that.  I am also a
young entrepreneur president of Conf
Commercio, that part is my responsibility
.  But in short, 120
also needs to be said to those who perhaps follow you, want
to be an entrepreneur, want to be a
founder, there is an all-encompassing job.  There
are no great results without great
effort, without great commitment.   Do you
still see yourself on Weoad in the future
?  Total 100 million per country at
least in Europe it's half the same in
Europe and one always talks about the unicorn
unicorn.  I would like to do Exactly.  The
first goal is a billion in
turnover, or more precisely 1 billion3 which
for us means 1 million
rodaders per year.  In a
geopolitical context like today's, thinking
that we build bridges instead is really
cool.
And in your opinion, what is the
greatest contribution you could make to Wirold
in the next 5 years?
My responsibility in the company is the
strategy part beyond the investment
relations.  Given the pace
of the company, the corporate culture, and the
new opportunities, my role is
to keep the bar high and the
pace intense.  At that point it was
time to go to the Rookis, an event
dedicated to small entrepreneurs
organized by Italian Funders Fan.
All three of FF on today Jar, I
Brom Hat and Pillar.
Here we are, here we are.
Give me a second, I'll be right there.
But does anyone pay the rent if you are
guests?
No, I pay for a piece.
You pay for the services, maybe.  I think
you are our guests.  Now I'm investigating.  But do
you pay rent to be here?  Oh,
so they're our guests,
so I'm having fun too,
and they don't even pay you the speaker fee.
Eh, you realize, you understand?   I
have to talk about the beginnings here are the
rookis.  I want to start a business.   They
asked me to talk about your first steps
as an entrepreneur and tell the
Paolo of the time a little about
what you would do.
Bravo.
Hi everyone, thanks for coming.   I do
n't know how we are doing with the times.  Now
I'm talking with this photo behind me.  Then he has
two microphones because Marcello Scani is also
here.  We're shooting the video
with him.  Scuola Zo was born for fun,
following a passion, without a business
plan, and has never had investors.  There are
two approaches to doing business.  There's
the approach where you study the market,
see a gap and try to seize it and
there's one that's a little more passion-driven.   There
is no right or wrong.  But what I
missed at that stage was
mentorship.  Zo School
grew up in Learny by Mistakes.  In
my opinion, the even more correct question is not
how you find the mentor, but how
you cultivate the relationship and how you maintain
trust.  At that point they put
a photo of Paolo from Airbnb as the background,
finding it ironic that Airbnb
has now led the investment round, but
only a few years ago Paolo was in
their offices dreaming of being as cool
as them.
Many of the meeting rooms you see here
at C30 were actually
inspired by BM's San
Francisco office.  There are some crazy meeting rooms
.  I still have the folder from
that trip with some notes on
how to make a cool office.
Obviously, the
call to action for young people was not missing on stage.  I'm making an
appeal, since there are many people here
who want to start a business, perhaps they have seized
the opportunity that before leaving, it
might make sense to do an experience as a
Founder Associate.  We have a
great position open at both Wroad
and Brom for Founder
Associate licenses.  Some with a more
marketing edge, some with a more PM edge,
some with a more SES edge.
At that point, straight home, Paolo didn't
take the phone away from his face the
whole time.  It's not usually like that, I
know.  It's really been
overrun by everyone these days, this time with
investors. I take the metro to Cadorna and then
switch to a bike and cycle
home.  This way of moving also
reflects Paolo's personality
.  Arrived home, just
moved.  Here you were telling me,
meanwhile here I see he just moved.
Bianca did so much on
April 14th, we moved, doing the
clearing work during the
round process on April 28th and the
closing on May 5th.  So it's been
a few weeks that I can't even tell you about, but
yes, I'm happy because before there were
100 of us guarding three children, it was
impossible.  Here we're renting,
but it's a little larger, so I'm
happy.
And you can see the Velasca tower.  There it is.
Yes. Infantte is nice because the Torre
Velasca turns the lights on at 9:30 and
turns them off at midnight, while the Duomo and the
castle are always on. At
midnight it turns them off, which is when
Bianca has to eat.  And you feel a bit like
a founder like you with a company
worth millions of millions, but why does he go back
on the subway and then break his bike?
That is, no sense in getting home.
Well, but it is the most convenient means of transport for
Milan,
it is the fastest.
Bi, metro 11, total 15. Then you saw
I have to take the Bimby to school by bike.
How do you take the kids to school?  Excuse me.   So
now there's Giorgio who's
behind and Carlo who's riding his
bike.  I'm
actually from Milan.  You're making me drink
a caichera.
Okino who introduced me to my partner
Mattia.  This is Sardinian excellence.  In
my opinion it goes very well with fish.
Let's look here.  Oh mama.
Hurray.  Thank you Mascello for being here.
Hurray!  Hurray.
I was invited to dinner.  I had never
seen your house.
I think you're the first.  What did we
do here?  We threw with my partner,
my parents, his parents and you.
The third one who enters the house.
There is a third one who enters the house.
Isn't it ever good like this?  Come on.
Thank you.  It's a fillet cooked in the oven and it's
good like this.  At that point we sat down
to eat.  The idea was to set up a microphone,
film Paolo and his wife Livia, and
then continue chatting, seeing
what emerged.  Obviously we talked a lot
, so I'll keep the
most relevant parts for you.  For example, how
does Paolo manage the fact that a
major part of his wealth—I'd say the
majority of his wealth—
hundreds of millions are tied up in the
company, and he chose during the round
to make a small secondary investment to
try to liquidate some of his
shares and take home some cash,
something that in Italy may seem taboo,
but in reality is very common among
entrepreneurs.  How does it feel to have
a gigantic fortune on your credit card, on a piece of paper, and in online articles,
probably quantifiable
in hundreds of millions of euros,
but it's all there after years and years and years of
working on it.  How does he handle
this part here.  I'm happy for the
teams and they believed in us and used
stock options and they are finally starting to
have some value.  I'm happy because
within the round there was
a small window of secondary investments, which in my opinion
is a big taboo in Italy,
but is the norm
internationally, and which in my opinion is
fundamental because the bulk
of the value is a pepper, but after a
very intense period in which
you worked, you pushed, if you gave
business to get to the
round, it means that the business is
working, then you pushed to
get to the closing because it's something of a
devastating intensity and the fact that
then at that moment you receive
capital to continue growing
the company, but you also receive from me, the
founder, to my C-founders.
The employees who had stock
options have the opportunity to
remunerate something.  We have made
secondary employees worth a few hundred
thousand euros.  I
made a couple of million which maybe allows you
to have a slightly bigger house.
Tonight we're having dinner with you and the nanny.
I have to ask Livia to be the one to
carry the weight of more things, then she
brings home the stress and she
gives me a lot of advice by doing chars, so she
has to do her job, wife,
mother and also my job because she does
the advice for us practically.  But
in Italy, in my opinion, it's something that's a bit of a
taboo, not all
investors are happy about it, because I
was actually against it, because
obviously if you sell today and you're
giving up a damn damage tomorrow and
so I was a bit against it, but my
investors suggested to me, I
mean, they're the investors I
told you about, to do secondary,
take home a
sufficient amount of money.   Do you know
what it is?  In my opinion they are not
sprints, they are marathons.  Managing
all this, however,
means bringing home a lot of stress.
[music] Anything you can
relieve stress at home allows you
to then convert it into energy for what
you're doing.  If you believe in the
family side, that is, doing business doesn't
necessarily mean closing the
work you're doing on one side and
your family on the other [music].  If he becomes
an entrepreneur because his entire
family believes in him, from his family
of origin to the family he
built for himself, therefore to me and his children.
And so the fact that there is this
possibility of being able to feel better
so that we can all move in the same direction is
fundamental, right?
Listen, would you hire Paolo, you
who are Char?
It depends on what you're doing.  He's a visionary,
so he's someone who definitely
sees opportunities, and that's an
incredible asset for a company.  The
big advantage of working with him is
that he can come up with great ideas and
execution at the same time, but he
constantly messes up your [music]
plan.  Well, it's the same in the
family, and
you have to find people who complement
you.  Exactly, you need to know what
your strengths are, what your weaknesses are
, find people who
complement you,
and how your CEO hired and how he
continues to hire.  And that's the reason
why we can stay together
because objectively we have areas
of strength and areas of improvement
that are absolutely complementary.  I
trust his
decisions extremely, so a
person could probably hire him if they trusted
him completely, that is, he should be
able to, I don't know, we managed to
close, so close the
round, make white [music] and move in within
a week, I'm not
kidding, set in 7 days he signed
Airbnb, I gave birth and we started
packing the boxes.  I put my
hand over my eyes and we kept going,
because I knew he would make it.
Then he's a little intense, no, as a person,
right?  Yes, he is not afraid that this stuff will
never end.  No, I have a dream,
but then
Thanks for the question, Marcello.  In the meantime,
I have the privilege of knowing him for
many years, and by many I mean
that we have known each other for about 20 years
.
We're scouts together, me and
Ah, exactly.  When he called home
to hand over to the
squad members, [music] he
always called on Thursdays because when it was me
on Fridays I would rush to pick up
the phone.  We went off the rails from there,
talking about their
love story from the beginning until today, but
unfortunately this isn't a
gossip channel, so I'll spare you that
part, even though it will be very
funny and interesting, and let's move
on.
I can tell you what he said about organizing
parties, I quote.  Do you see it?
At a certain point they even revealed to me
that it was Olivia who pushed
Paolo to continue towards the closing of the
round.  I wasn't entirely convinced,
I had an assessment in mind, a
different ticket than the one you'll get and I
was really torn about whether to have
another operation, right?  It was
fundamental,
it was important, that's what takes
time, right?  [music] So, if
we can say the round, at a certain point
in the overall difficulty, we said
"Okay, this is the decision we've
made, we're not going back from here,
we have to close this out."  There was still
doubt as to whether to close it or not.  On that
trip we decided that it had to be
closed, it had to be done.
How lucky.
My family is essential to me right now.  I discovered this great
passion, for example, of knowing how to be a
mother, because it's something I didn't know
you could learn, I didn't know you
could study, [music] instead, yes, you
can do it.  At this moment, it is essential for me
that the three of them are happy and
grow up, because I feel very strongly not the
intense maternity, the mother hen who
takes care of them, but the social calling [music]
to bring people into the world
who will change something.
Doing a round is a marathon and you'll have
crazy energy spikes where it
feels like you're going to the next one.  Anyway,
you have incredible downs, arguments at home,
team members who burn out, you who
burn out and have a solid couple,
solid friends who keep us
calm because then maybe you can
chat with friends.   Once
the round is over,
what is your long-term goal?
Making Weoad a global community.   We would
really like a million passengers by 2031, then who knows,
maybe we can replicate it in some age groups,
why not?  You're not saying you don't get tired at
some point.
Yes, if you don't take into account that as the
company grows,
your role will also evolve.   There
is no scenario you wish for.  The
thing that I would really like is that in my opinion
Bendy is doing a
wonderful thing because he is showing
in Italy that it is possible.
[clearing throat] I would like there to
be others after Bendy and I
would like me to be one of them
because they have really created in the order
of hundreds of millionaires among the team
members of the company, the scaleup startup that
transforms a
nobody into a millionaire in 5 to 10 years which is a really
cool thing that will then generate investments
in the startup 20 years ago, that is, it's really
cool.  This second episode with
Paolo was fantastic, also because
if I barely knew him the first time,
over the years he has become a friend from
whom I have often had the opportunity to learn
a lot, even for my
entrepreneurial journey. I'm happy
that despite my commitments, he managed to
dedicate a day to record the
video together.  Let me know what
this video has left you with, which other
entrepreneurs you would like to see here on the
channel and continue to follow me so as not to
miss the next ones.